RASHID QAMAR

Site Engineer (Civil Engineer)

Ramgarh (829108), Jharkhand

\(+917667638466 \) \(\square \) qamarrashid3883@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rashid-qamar-95660b246

SUMMARY:-

I currently work at Sumintra Fiber & Décor Pvt Ltd. And I

have been appointed here to constructing a water park here, I have good command over Excavation layouting, Working drawing and good knowledge in construction of Swimming pool, Contour reading and Water treatment plant etc. Am a Innovative Civil Engineer having working experience of 1 year 8 month in Estimation, Quantity Surveying & Rate Analysis, Bar Bending Schedule (BBS) and some knowledge about 2D Auto-CAD Drawing for various residential project for Vikas Kumar Singh Pvt. Ltd. Having good command over Estimation, BBS and survey with Auto-level with different academics projects and achievements proven skills like preparing D.P.R, BOQ, BBS various bill like Item Wise Bill, Slab Rate Bill, Government Bill along with Centre Line Layout or Township Layout and Site Execution with Team.

OBJECTIVE:-

Seeking for an opportunity in a reputed company where I can work individually or in a Team to utilized and nourish my in-Depth knowledge and experience for the development of the company.

EXPERIENCE:-

❖ Sumintra Fibre and Décor Private Ltd (SFDPL)

Plot No. G1/G2/G3, Phase-IV, Bokaro Industrial Area, Bokaro, Jharkhand-827014 Gmail:- saturnfibre@gmail.com [Working Year – January 2024 to August 2024]

Project Name:- MHA Water Park & Resort

Location: Ranchi-Tata Highway, Jareya village, Rampur, Ranchi (Jharkhand) Tender Value: Rs. 9,50,00,000/- (9.5 Cr) approx.

- Played a quality & their paperwork.
- Extensively involved in **Execution work** and **daily progress documentation**.
- Focused on minor but vital areas such as Finishing Detailing, Quantity Estimation.
- Supplemented on project planning and scheduling with senior engineer.
- Sound knowledge in understanding all type of **Drawings** and fully study specification of task which related to **construction task**.
- Played vital role in performing contouring of the Plot and Planning for building position along with profile levelling for road mapping.
- Preparation of Detailed Quantity Estimates, Scheduled of Quantity, Rate Analysis and Measurement Sheets.
- Joint Measurement / Re-measurement at Site.
- Preparing Bill of Quantity according to D.S.R.
- Reading and correlating drawing and specifications, identifying the item of works and preparing the bill of items.
- Preparing **B.B.S** and filling in the **Measurement Book**.



* Civil Guruji (Civil Engineering Training Institute)

Harmu, Ranchi, (Jharkhand)

[Training Period – Two Month of Corporate Training Course from August 2023 to September 2023]

Project Name :- Sanik School Complex

Tender Value :- Rs. 82,23,410.8 /-

- Preparation of Detailed Quantity Estimates , Scheduled of Quantity , Rate Analysis and Measurement Sheets.
- Joint Measurement / Re-measurement at Site.
- Preparing Bill of Quantity according to D.S.R.
- Reading and correlating drawing and specifications, identifying the item of works and preparing the bill of items.
- Preparing B.B.S and filling in the Measurement Book.

❖ Vikas Kumar Singh Pvt. Ltd. (Government & undertaking Contractor)

Kankerbagh, Patna, (Bihar)

[Working Year – July 2022 to July 2023]

Project Name: - Repair & Maintaining Residencial Complex.

Tender Value :- Rs 5,00,00,000 /-

- Played a quality & their paperwork.
- Extensively involved in Execution work and daily progress documentation.
- Focused on minor but vital areas such as Finishing Detailing, Quantity Estimation.
- Supplemented on **project planning** and **scheduling** with senior engineer.
- Sound knowledge in understanding all type of **Drawings** and fully study specification of task which related to **construction task**.
- Played vital role in **performing contouring** of the **Plot and Planning for building position along with profile levelling for road mapping.**

Central Coalfield Ltd. (C.C.L)

Morabadi, Ranchi, (Jharkhand)

[Internship Period – One month of practical training given by collage campus , I have done on November 2021]

EDUCATION:-

Diploma In Civil Engineering (Percentage − 70%)

AL – Kabir Polytechnic Collage (Jharkhand University Of Technology) [Passing Year 2019 - 2022]

❖ Intermediate In Science "I.Sc" (Percentage − 70%)

Sri Agrasen School, Central Board Of Secondary Education (CBSE) Passing Year 2018 – 2020

❖ Matriculation "10th"

(Percentage-83.4%)

Sri Agrasen School , Central Board Of Secondary Education (CBSE) [Passing Year 2017- 2018]

SOFTWARE SKILLS:-

- **★** AutoCAD 2D designing and making of a complete submission drawing including Floor Plan, Section Plan, Elevation, Site Plan, Location Plan and Area Schedule.
- * <u>AutoCAD</u>- 3D Drawing to making designing of **Exterior** and **Interior**
- Google Sketchup Using for 3D modelling, making detailing work of interior and Exterior of drawing and doing some detailing work of structural plan.
- Lumion & Enscape Using for Rendering of 3D drawing to make realistic and Aesthetic view of exterior and interior of the drawing to so more clearing concept of client.
- **EPR** My Build Cost (MBC) I used Build Cost Application that serves a versatile Estimation Tool, encompassing a wide range of Construction Element such as Excavation, Concrete Quantities, Plastering, Painting, Flooring And More.
- ★ MS Excel I used MS Excel to create Surveying Task, Profile Levelling, Contouring, Billing and many more.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- ➤ Item Wise detailed Estimation of a complete building as per CPWD-DSR rate with the help of the EPR model (Quantity Take-off Tool).
- ➤ AutoCAD Submission drawing, Elevation and Section drawing.
- Quantity of materials and Rate Analysis Under CPWD guideline and rule.
- ▶ BBS (Bar Bending Schedule) Preparing detailed BBS of complete Building Structure using MS EXCEL. As per my responsibilities, I meticulously prepared a Bar Bending Schedule, ensuring the correct placement of Steel Reinforcement in the Concrete Structure.
- This involved specification the exact Location, Length, and Shape of the Bar, ensuring optimal strength and durability in accordance with the projects design and engineering specification.
- Surveying Prepare Contouring Levelling, Profile levelling using AUTO-LEVEL instrument.
- ▶ **DPR** Maintain Daily Progress Report in MS Excel and Sheet Paper.
- Layout Centreline Layout, Brickwork and Township Layout.
- Deals with **contractor** and **Client** with their Mutual understanding.
- **Site Inspection , Supervision , Organizing and Co-ordination of the Site Activities.**
- **Good Communication Skill and Time Management.**
- Effective Team Building and Negotiating Skills.

I hereby declare that the above mentioned information is correct to the best of my knowledge and belief

DATE :- 1 OCT 2024 PLACE:- Ranchi ER. RASHID QAMAR